[Music]
But then in the right above I talk about something called after state I just
wanted to mention very quickly so what is after state it's a
very interesting concept or
so in many problem instances especially
things like games and like this kind of
mean like a system there are moves
by
nature right so there are moves by the human
moves by nature or moves by an ponent rather so that the
whole situation in the
system is introduced either by this ponent
and by nature right their action the factor their
action in the system is deterministic but you don't know what
the ponent will do so in this case of
nature lock
ageing and the lock their action is selling kwt
tm y cell kg gan firm y y t you know the defect to you
make a move then the piece moves r n s t t t t t t t t t t t t t t t t t t t t t
t
So if you don't have to do something okay it
actually lands up in the square that you
want to go to
and you have to consider all the quality
but then you don't know where the component is going to do so if you look at
the actual state
transition dynamics it's going to look at the
caustic but that's the deterministic
component and then there's the caustic
component so some times it makes it a little more difficult to come up with a
solution if you pull
out the deterministic component separately
and represent a cross as an after
state so when an after state some sum or take a square and
apply a to it so
you get to some other
space which is called a
prime
and now all the state applies to the state in the as a result state
taking so some sum or
after state taking a
function on the value
over the element in the after state I can learn a  The
v function over the entries in s prime this
is essentially a combination of s cross a so
the v function over s prime is almost like
learning a q function and what is the advantage
of learning this v function over s prime instead
of q o s cross a if I have
one less dimension and anything else is
one less dimension okay then I
explain that in the
writer so it could be many
state action p same a
prime l
taks re brief taking to a n different way
in yd [ __ ] yer rat so I de r ch way yt de yer rat I could f ur
apple I could f ur I could go d er rat
and
f ur I'd go d er
rat so this is the state and action was put across yer
but both had the same after state
and sy action from yer I'm going to be the same this n
after state rat this  If
a prime
is in a given state then it is going to have equal number of axes in it. If a prime is in a given state then it is going to have equal
number of axes in it. If a prime is in a given state then it will have x more than x. If I am
playing a game when ever I see the
board when ever I have to make a move they will be
equal number of axes in it. But if a prime is in a given state then it will have x more than x. So it is actually a different
set of states. They are not
really states. I mean I might not see them in reality.
For example, in
the given task, after states are possibly states. I
mean, they cannot be states. They are also states.
After states are also states. But in this
case, after states are not
states. Because you will never see a state that has a more axes than x, so what is in it. If a
prime is in a given state then
it could be the same as x, but it could also be different,
but  The point here was this: I actually
write a value
function over the state (taken as a subset of the action) and since the whole thing
is deterministic, if I know the rules of
the game, I can do the look ahead.
So, I give you a state. I look at all
possible after
states, and then I pick an action that leads
me to the best possible after
state. I can do the look ahead. Because it's
only the application of the action, I don't have to
model nature. Right, I only have to model
what happens when I apply my action
to it. So, it's a plus or minus look
ahead. And this is how Jerry Tesro
implemented his back game. He also learned
a value function over
state actions. He learned a value function over after states, and he also learned a value function over after
states. Right, once the die
roll is determined, you take an action. Right,
when you take an action, your state
includes the die roll. You know the
die roll then.  What ever action you would take that would be
deterministic and then ponent would
actually make nondeterministic would make sot fi que ok sot br
au chapter so some point i do
some proof sketches for 0 and possibly
cunning but it might not be next week and see
andone
chapter
[music]
[applause]